Peigeng Jiang

(+61) 499-482-349 • jiangpeigeng@gmail.com • Visa type: Temporary graduate visa 485 • GitHub: https://github.com/AndyJPG

OBJECTIVE

Aim to work as a web developer. Had experience in building SaaS application using mainly React and Node JS. Provided solutions to fix application issues and improve performance. Increased efficiency of customer statement calculation process by integrating Python code and Excel. Automated calculation process to minimize human calculation error by 80%. Had experience in Agile working environment and familiar with sprint planning, scrum meeting, and sprint retro. I also had experience in Graphic Design and responsible for thumbnailing, concept development, visual exploration and concept refinement in design projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

B&E Foods / Developer

Sep 2020 - Nov 2020

B&E Foods is a boning specialist and a wholesaler of poultry products.

Melbourne, Australia

- Improved process in getting customer data by using queries on Excel to retrieve data from Microsoft cloud database
- Improved precision in selecting desirable data by filtering and integrating data using SQL query string on Excel
- Designed consistent customer statement format by organizing Excel sheet using VBA code
- Reduced time in producing customer statements by 70% by processing and calculating data with Python, and presenting data with Excel
- Reduced human error in customer statement calculation process by 60% by processing and calculating data with Python
- Increased simplicity for non-technical staff to produce customer statements by creating interactive elements on Excel sheets using VBA code

B&E Foods / Developer Intern

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

B&E Foods is a boning specialist and a wholesaler of poultry products.

Melbourne, Australia

- Increased visibility for the stock purchase team to compare history product purchase price by calculating and highlighting differences using Python and present in Excel
- Increased online store conversion rate by 40% by reducing website loading time
- Reduced online store website loading time by 80% by removing excessive DOM elements
- Increased online store website performance score on Google by 64% by removing excessive DOM elements

CAFEEZY / Full-stack developer Intern

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

A digital solution firm aims to provide an online platform for catering businesses.

Melbourne, Australia

- Improved application's performance in creating new items by 90% by removing unused React components from re-rendering
- Developed functionality for users to check their sales history in daily, weekly, monthly, and yearly format by creating sales history interval to retrieve integrated and filtered data
- Published and hosted single page website by using AWS S3 bucket
- Developed dynamic contact form for the static website by using AWS API Gateway, AWS SES and Node JS to develop AWS Lambda function.
- Developed customizable AWS serverless mailing function by creating documentation for the lambda function and publishing it on GitHub
- · Performed application version control by using Git
- Enhanced application code integrity by using ESLint to enforce coding style

DUÜET / Graphic Designer

Dec 2018 - Oct 2019

https://www.duuet.com.au/

A photography firm focusing on wedding photography and videography.

Melbourne, Australia

- Increased the visual appearance of existing website by redesigning the website to align with design trend
- Designed digital and physical contents for display and presentation purpose by using Adobe Photoshop and InDesign
- Managed company online posts and digital contents by using WordPress back-end panel

T-ONE IMAGE / Graphic Designer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2019

https://www.t-oneimage.com.au/

A photography firm focusing on wedding photography and videography.

Melbourne, Australia

- Managed company website contents and social media contents by using WordPress and social media platform
- Designed posters, printouts and brochures for presentation and advertising purpose by using Adobe InDesign and Photoshop
- Increased brand awareness by redesigning company website to align with company strategies and design trend
- Improved UI and UX by collaborating with developers to modify front-end code

T-ONE IMAGE / Graphic Design Intern

A photography firm focusing on wedding photography and videography.

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017 Melbourne, Australia

PIPEX / Graphic Design Intern

Jan 2016 - Dec 2016 Melbourne, Australia

- Created visual identity design by using Adobe InDesign, Photoshop and Illustrator
- Designed advertising poster, print out, media content and brochure by using Adobe Photoshop and InDesign
- Improved website UI and UX by using Sketch and Adobe Photoshop
- Supported front end programmer in developing visual content by using Adobe Photoshop to create UI components

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

OhFarm Application Project

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

Programmer

Melbourne

- Designed a platform in providing kitchen gardening information by developing an iOS application using Swift and XCode IDE
- Created simple server for holding contents by storing contents in AWS S3 bucket with an accessible API gateway for retrieving data
- Increased the precision of information for kitchen plants by researching relevant datasets on Kaggle and government open data website and processing data with **Python**
- Improved visual appearance by designing UI components with Adobe Photoshop
- Improved user experience by conducting random user tests and target user surveys and refining the application based on feedback
- Managed each sprint cycle by performing sprint planning meeting, daily stand-up meeting, sprint review, and sprint retrospective
- Project link: github.com/AndyJPG/OhFarmV2.0.git

Cafeezy Website Redesign

Nov 2019 - Dec 2019

Graphic Designer

Melbourne

- Redesigned Cafeezy website visual appearance by researching the company's goal, strategy and design trend, and creating prototypes using Adobe Photoshop
- Created website demonstration for presentation purpose by designing interactive website using Adobe XD
- Finalized visual appearance by conducting a presentation to key stakeholders and do modifications based on feedback

Duuet Wedding Photography Website Redesign

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

Graphic Designer

Melbourne

- Increased brand awareness by redesigning Duuet website to align with its company strategies, goals and design trend
- Managed design process by performing essential research, brainstorming, ideation, drafting, creation, and finalizing work based on feedback
- Created new Duuet website by using Adobe Photoshop
- Website: https://www.duuet.com.au

SKILLS

Programming Skills: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Git

Design Skills: UI design, Graphic design **Computer Skills:** Adobe suite, Microsoft Office

Language Skills: Fluent in Mandarin

Soft Skills: Effective communication skill, Problem-solving, Teamwork, Presentation, Adaptability, Logical thinking, Time

management

EDUCATION

Monash University *Master Degree in Information Technology*

Jul 2017 - Jul 2019 Melbourne, Australia GPA: 2.7 (WAM: 70.4)

Deakin University Melbourne, Australia

Bachelor of Design (Visual Communication Design)

GPA: 3.04 / 4.00 (Core GPA: 3.16)

Honors/Awards: Graduate with High Distinction (2017)

Holmesglen Institute TAFE Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

Advance Diploma of Graphic Design Melbourne, Australia

Jul 2016 - Jul 2017

Holmesglen Institute TAFE Jan 2014 - Dec 2014

Diploma of Graphic Design Melbourne, Australia

REFEREES

Available upon request